const e="economics",o=200,t=70,a=[{id:112,question:"Price discrimination exists when  ",option:{a:"The same product of the same quality is sold for different prices of the same buyer  ",b:"The same product of the same quality is sold for different prices to different buyers  ",c:"Different products are sold for the same price to the same buyers  ",d:"Different products are sold for the same price to different buyers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:113,question:"A commodity is said to be price inelastic if  ",option:{a:"Changes in the quantity purchased of a good is less than proportionate changes in its price  ",b:"Changes in the quantity purchased of a good is proportional to changes in its price  ",c:"Changes in the quantity purchased of a good is more than proportionate changes in its price  ",d:"The quantity purchased of a good never responds to change in its price."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:114,question:"The parameter ‘b’ in a consumption function of the form; C = a + bY; where Y is the National income is  ",option:{a:"Marginal benefit of consumption  ",b:"Marginal propensity to purchase  ",c:"Marginal propensity to consume  ",d:"Marginal propensity to save "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:115,question:"Indifference curve and isoquant are respectively relevant is  ",option:{a:"Theories of consumer behaviours and production  ",b:"Theories of human indifference and production  ",c:"Theories of trade and production  ",d:"Theories of production and trade"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:116,question:"Perfect price elastic supply means  ",option:{a:"No change in supply as price changes  ",b:"Any change in price completely stops supply  ",c:"Changes in price double supply  ",d:"A change in price leads to proportionate change in supply"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:117,question:"Change in demand and change in quantity demanded are not the same because  ",option:{a:"All factors affecting change in demand also affect change in quantity demanded except income  ",b:"All factors affecting change in demand are not affecting change in quantity demanded except income  ",c:"Many factors leads to change in demand but only change in price affect change in quantity demanded   ",d:"Many factors leads to change in demand but only change in income affect change in quantity demanded"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:118,question:"The following is the main difference between firm and industry  ",option:{a:"Industry is the group of firms producing related products  ",b:"Industry is the group of firms in the manufacturing sector  ",c:"Industry is the group of firms in different sectors of the economy  ",d:"Industry is the group of firms with a single pressure group"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:119,question:"Roles of central bank include the following except  ",option:{a:"Lender of last resort to commercial bank  ",b:"Banker to commercial bank  ",c:"Regulator to both the money and capital markets ",d:"Receipt  of government deposits"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:120,question:"Ordinary shareholders and preferential shareholders are different because ",option:{a:"Preferential shareholders participate and can vote and be voted for during the  AGM  ",b:"ordinary shareholders are given priority in case the company is liquidated  ",c:"Preferential shareholders are prominent shareholders than ordinary shareholders  ",d:"Ordinary shareholders are the core shareholders in the company"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:121,question:" Yam and palm oil are together; therefore  ",option:{a:"Yam is a substitute good while palm oil is a complementary good  ",b:"Yam is complimentary good while palm oil is a substitute good  ",c:"Yam and oil are complimentary goods ",d:"Yam and beans are substitute goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:122,question:"Private and public limited liability companies are not the same because  ",option:{a:"Former is limited to fifty shareholders but not the later  ",b:"both are not legal entities  ",c:"Former is established secretly but latter is located in central places  ",d:"Former is managed by board of directors but latter is managed by board of management."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:123,question:"If salary of worker increases from 50,000 to 80,000 Naira and average price of certain commodities consumed by the worker increase from 120 Naira to 160 Naira then  ",option:{a:"The nominal income increases but leave the real income constant  ",b:"The real income increases, but nominal income has reduced  ",c:"The nominal income increases, but real income decreases  ",d:"Both the nominal and real income increase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:124,question:"Discount rate means  ",option:{a:"Rate at which money are borrowed from commercial bank  ",b:"Rate at which bank receive deposit from the public  ",c:"Central bank rate on the money borrowed by commercial banks  ",d:"Commercial bank rate on the money borrowed from other commercial bank"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:125,question:"When the government expenditure and income are the same in fiscal year, this is referred as;",option:{a:"Net balance  ",b:"Zero balanced budget  ",c:"Balanced budget  ",d:"Net income "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:126,question:"Inflation as a result of increase in the payment for factors of production is called  ",option:{a:"Cost-pull inflation  ",b:"Demand-push inflation  ",c:"Cost-push inflation  ",d:"Demand pull inflation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:127,question:"When Lump-sun tax is paid by a producer, it means that;  ",option:{a:"The tax is paid proportional to the quantity of output produced  ",b:"The tax is paid regardless of volume of output  ",c:"The tax is paid in arrears  ",d:"The tax is returned to the producer after the payment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:128,question:"The following is not correct  ",option:{a:"Average variable cost equals average total cost minus average fixed cost   ",b:"Average fixed cost equals average variable cost minus average total cost  ",c:"Average total cost equals average variable cost plus average fixed cost  ",d:"Average total cost minus average variable cost equals average fixed cost "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:129,question:"Normal profit means;  ",option:{a:"All the accountant cost are covered but not all the economist cost  ",b:"All the economist cost are covered but not all the accountant cost  ",c:"More than economist cost are covered  ",d:"None of the economist and Accountant costs is covered "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:130,question:"If the price of commodity X increases because of the increase in the price vis-à-vis the increase in demand  for other commodities are likely to be  ",option:{a:"Complimentary  ",b:"Substitute  ",c:"Compose  ",d:"Intermediate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:131,question:"The following may not inflate the National Income figure ",option:{a:"Student’s bursary  ",b:"Owners occupied houses  ",c:"Office Inducement  ",d:"Intermediate goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:132,question:"Legal Entity means  ",option:{a:"A company is owned by large number of people  ",b:"A company is owned by small number of people  ",c:"A company is insulated against litigation  ",d:"A company is not insulated against litigation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:133,question:"In the ownership structure of joint stock company the following is correct;  ",option:{a:"Ordinary shareholders are stronger than preferential shareholders  ",b:"Preferential shareholder are stronger than ordinary shareholders  ",c:"Ordinary shareholders are settled first in case of company’s liquidation  ",d:"Ordinary and preferential shareholders are perpetual rivals "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:134,question:"The difference between the output proceedings of Nigerians abroad and foreigners in Nigeria is known as;  ",option:{a:"Net export to abroad  ",b:"Net import from abroad  ",c:"Net income from abroad  ",d:"Net income to abroad"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:135,question:"A stock variable is measured;  ",option:{a:"Over a period  ",b:"At a point  ",c:"Consistently  ",d:"Intermittently "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:136,question:"The following is not true of price mechanism ",option:{a:"Equilibrium price is determined by forces of demand and supply  ",b:"Individual households and firms pursue personal interest  ",c:"Producers and consumers are rational in decision making ",d:"Price control in prominent in the commodity and input markets."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:271,question:"Human wants are",option:{a:"Limited",b:"scarce",c:"unlimited",d:"in grades"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:272,question:"The difference between the money cost and the real cost of any item is that",option:{a:"real cost is the alternative forgone while the money cost is the actual amount paid for buying the item",b:"the real cost is the opportunity cost, while the money cost is the marginal cost",c:"money cost is the opportunity cost, while the real cost is the actual cost in monetary terms",d:"money cost is always greater than real cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:273,question:"The Production Possibility Curve (PPC) indicates that as 	more of one good is produced",option:{a:"less of the other good is produced",b:"the same quantity of the other good is produced",c:"more of the other good is produced",d:"none of the other good is produced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:274,question:"An arrangement of data in rows and columns is referred to as a",option:{a:"Graph",b:"bar chart",c:"pie chart",d:"Table"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:275,question:"A normal demand curve slopes",option:{a:"downwards from left to right",b:"upwards from right to left",c:"downwards from right to left",d:"upwards from left to right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:276,question:"The co-efficient of income elasticity of demand for inferior goods is",option:{a:"Positive",b:"equal to one",c:"less than one",d:"negative"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:277,question:"If a 20% rise in the price of  Whisky leads to a 30% increase in quantity demanded of Schnapps, the cross elasticity of demand is",option:{a:"3.0",b:"2.5",c:"2.3",d:"1.5"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:278,question:"Palm oil and palm kernel have",option:{a:"competitive supply",b:"excess supply",c:"joint supply",d:"composite supply"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:279,question:"A supply curve which is vertical has an elasticity co-efficient of",option:{a:"0",b:"0.5",c:"1.5",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:280,question:"If the current price of an apple is twice that of last year, it implies that the value of money is",option:{a:"Stable",b:"falling",c:"rising",d:"getting stronger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:281,question:"Price fixed above the equilibrium is to",option:{a:"protect agricultural producers",b:"discourage agricultural producers",c:"lower the prices of agricultural produce",d:"favour consumers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:282,question:"A consumer purchasing a commodity X will maximize his satisfaction if",option:{a:"Px = Mux",b:"Px  >_  MUx",c:"Px > Mux",d:"Px < Mux"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:283,question:"When total utility is constant, it means marginal utility is",option:{a:"Increasing",b:"zero",c:"decreasing",d:"one"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:284,question:"A rational consumer is one who",option:{a:"spends his income to maximize satisfaction",b:"is not influenced by advertisement",c:"behaves in a particular way all the time",d:"knows the prices of all goods and buys the cheapest"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:285,question:"Which of the following is not true about land?",option:{a:"The supply is fixed",b:"Land is mobile",c:"It is subject to diminishing returns",d:"Land is heterogeneous"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:286,question:"The type of production that involves the tapping and 	harnessing of natural resources is",option:{a:"primary production",b:"secondary production",c:"tertiary production",d:"industrial production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:287,question:"Which of the following does not change in the short run?",option:{a:"Variable cost",b:"Marginal cost",c:"Total cost",d:"Fixed cost"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:288,question:"The resources used in production are called",option:{a:"variable inputs",b:"factors of production",c:"capital for production",d:"fixed inputs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:289,question:"A firm will shut down in the long run if its earning is",option:{a:"less than normal profit",b:"greater than normal profit",c:"equal to super normal profit",d:"less than super normal profit"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:290,question:"A market structure where profit is maximized when marginal 	revenue, marginal cost and price are equal is known as",option:{a:"perfect competition",b:"monopoly",c:"oligopoly",d:"imperfect competition"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:291,question:"In which of the following markets does a firm have power to 	make super normal profits both in the short run and long run?",option:{a:"Monopol",b:"Duopoly",c:"Oligopoly",d:"Monopsony"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:292,question:"If there arc no barriers to entering a market, it means that",option:{a:"anyone can become a buyer or seller",b:"unwanted goods can always enter the market",c:"the market becomes a dumping ground",d:"the goods are not inspected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:293,question:"A firm’s main aim is to",option:{a:"survive in business",b:"maximize profits",c:"increase its market share",d:"satisfy the ambitions of its managers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:294,question:"One good reason for the elimination of middlemen is that they",option:{a:"cause increase in price",b:"help in price stability",c:"grade and blend goods",d:"are too many"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:295,question:"The increase in population growth in big cities is referred to as",option:{a:"settlement",b:"migration",c:"industrialization",d:"Urbanization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:296,question:"Frictional unemployment can be reduced by",option:{a:"encouraging the use of retraining schemes",b:"removing barriers to labour mobility",c:"restricting the introduction of new technology",d:"lowering the level of wages paid to young people"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:297,question:"If the labour force of a country is 2.5 million and 2 million are employed, what is the unemployment rate?",option:{a:"0.2%",b:"20%",c:"200%",d:"250%"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:298,question:"The grouping of population according to the economic activities people engage in is",option:{a:"age distribution",b:"sex distribution",c:"geographical distribution",d:"occupational distribution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:299,question:"Natural growth rate of population can be defined as the",option:{a:"difference between birth rate and death rate",b:"number of births in a year",c:"increase in the population growth in a year",d:"difference between the total population and the death rate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:300,question:"Which of the following is not a consequence of increased unemployment?",option:{a:"A fall in tax revenue for the government",b:"A reduction in trade union’s influence",c:"A fall in the death rate",d:"An increase in the labour force"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:301,question:"The following are features of subsistence agriculture except",option:{a:"little capital",b:"processing of raw materials",c:"small allotments of land",d:"use of crude implements"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:302,question:"Which of the following is not true of small companies?",option:{a:"The cannot benefit from economics of scale",b:"are a good source of new jobs",c:"can satisfy demand in specialist markets",d:"have a good record of technical innovations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:303,question:"The effect of privatization on the industrial sector of a country is that it",option:{a:"ensures efficiency",b:"discourages efficiency",c:"leads to decrease in output",d:"leads to liquidation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:304,question:"The production strategy used in an over populated country is",option:{a:"import substitution",b:"capital intensive",c:"labour intensive",d:"first come first employed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:305,question:"National income is used to measure",option:{a:"a country’s population size",b:"a country’s economic growth",c:"the human level of development",d:"the flow of imports to a country"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:306,question:"A tax is regressive if the",option:{a:"rate of tax is constant at all income levels",b:"rate of tax decreases as income increases",c:"rate of tax increases as income increases",d:"tax is direct rather than indirect"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:307,question:"When a country’s net income from abroad is added to its total 	output, the result is",option:{a:"gross domestic product",b:"net national product",c:"gross national product",d:"net domestic product"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:308,question:"A fall in national output will necessitate",option:{a:"a rise in expenditure on imports",b:"a rise in the level of savings",c:"an increase in consumption expenditure",d:"a rise in the standard of living"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:309,question:"The demand for money to take advantage of changes in bond 	prices is the",option:{a:"unforeseen motive",b:"transaction motive",c:"speculative motive",d:"precautionary motive"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:310,question:"Cost push inflation is caused by a",option:{a:"rise in the cost of production",b:"decrease in the transportation cost",c:"rise in demand for goods",d:"decrease in the cost of production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:311,question:"Deposits held in a commercial bank are part of",option:{a:"money supply",b:"transfer payments",c:"ordinary shares",d:"treasury bills"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:312,question:"One profitable form of business undertaken by the commercial banks is",option:{a:"the issuing of cheques",b:"the payment of standing order",c:"lending money to borrowers",d:"accepting cheques from customers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:313,question:"When governments want to discourage consumption, they 	tax goods whose demand",option:{a:"price inelastic",b:"abnormal in nature",c:"price elastic",d:"normal in nature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:314,question:"A rise in government expenditure can lead to",option:{a:"higher inflation",b:"higher unemployment",c:"lower profits for industries",d:"lower importation of raw materials by industries"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:315,question:"Tariff is used to protect domestic industries by making foreign goods relatively",option:{a:"cheaper in the domestic market",b:"more expensive in the domestic market",c:"more expensive in the international market",d:"cheaper in the international market"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:70,data:a};export{a as data,i as default,o as status,e as subject,t as total};
